# Heli Shah

(619) 736-6710 | helishah3010@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Portfolio website

## **SUMMARY:**

Prolific, Software Engineer with 6 years of history in Software industry which includes 3+ years of experience in Quality Assurance offering great attention to detail and commitment in not only improving product but also improving the process.

## **EDUCATION:**

MS in Computer Science.

August 2015 - Dec 2017

California State University, Long Beach, CA.

BS in Information Technology.

August 2009 - June 2013

Gujarat Technological University, India.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS:**

**QA Automation**: Cypress, Playwright, Gherkin, Puppeteer and Selenium.

**Manual Testing:** Test case writing, test planning, bug reporting, Web Accessibility testing (W3C WAI), Native Mobile app testing, Android Studio, Test Progress Reporting, Chrome Dev Tools, Xcode, Postman, New relic, Honeybadger, MySQL

**Responsive Website Development:** HTML5, CSS3, Javascript (ES6), OOP, Web hosting, WordPress, Bootstrap. **Other:** Microsoft Azure DevOps, Git, GitHub, VS Code, Docker

## **EXPERIENCE:**

### QA Engineer - II, Mindbody Inc.

April 2019 - Present

- Profiling Cypress E2E Test Automation framework for the React Micro Front End.
- Creating Test Progress Report and Test Summary Report using Microsoft Azure Dashboards to provide real-time information into the team's testing status for each sprint.
- Setup and executed testing on local, staging and production environments across different browsers and devices including Accessibility testing by following WAI Accessibility Standards.
- Native mobile app testing using Android Studio, Xcode and Proxyman.
- Monitored releases for performance using New Relic, Honey Badger and conducted post-release testing.
- Participate in Sprint Planning and Refinements to estimate the effort for each ticket and overall sprint.
- Act as SME and train new team members.

# Web Developer/SEO Specialist, Lansion Media Inc.

April 2018 - April 2019

- Planned, developed and hosted 8 different event and corporate based responsive websites using WordPress,
  Wix, PHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MySQL which increased brand awareness by 70%.
- Worked as a sole developer for the entire marketing team

# Junior PHP Developer, Infinitely Infinite Solutions, India

Sept 2013 - June 2014

- Enhanced e-commerce website made using Magento 1.8, PHP, HTML, CSS and MySQL.
- Verified successful interaction of 12 different 3<sup>rd</sup> party services and API.

### Certifications

LinkedIn: End-to-End JavaScript Testing with Cypress.io (Link)

June 2022

 Completed 300 hours of coursework comprising of accessibility as well as responsive web design projects using HTML5 and CSS3

FreeCodeCamp: JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures (Link)

June 2022

Completed 300 hours of coursework consisting of Object Oriented Javascript based projects.